Simon Meredith

UX & Service Design

simon@lerefuge.com +44 7825805466 www.lerefuge.co.uk Senior designer working in interaction and service design roles.

Most recently leading design for the new Apply for Legal Aid service (MoJ) and Marine Management Organisation inspection tool (Defra). I've also worked on multiple internal and public-facing BBC products and headed up design at a tech start-up across both responsive web and native apps.

I like being proactive and involved in all aspects of the design process. My experience in both small and large agile teams has strengthened my ability to communicate clearly and get people behind my designs.

Skills

Interaction design, workshop facilitation, storyboards, user flows, journey and service maps, prototyping, visual design, user research and testing

Tools: Sketch, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GOV.UK Prototyping Kit, Adobe CS, Proto.io, InVision, Google Suite, pen, paper, Miro, After Effects, Keynote

Experience

Engine Transformation, HMCTS & MMO (Defra) - Senior UX Designer

April 2019 - July 2019 & November 2019 - March 2020 (Multiple contracts)

Design and prototyping for a suite of internal apps recording all fishing activity across the UK. Two discovery phases for 11 tribunals.

Legal Aid Agency, MoJ - Senior Interaction Designer

April 2018 - April 2019 (Contract)

Design, prototypes (GOV.UK Prototyping Kit) and testing for the new legal aid application service from discovery through to private beta.

Veon & Shelter - UX Designer

January 2018 - April 2018 (Multiple contracts)

Re-design of onboarding flows for the Veon messaging app, increasing sign-up conversions. Two-week design sprint developing new donation formats.

BBC Internal Tools - UX Designer

June 2017 - January 2018 (Contract)

All design for BBC's new TV and Radio scheduling tool supporting a team of 10 developers. Responsible for insight, design, prototyping and testing.

Encore Musicians - Head of Design

October 2016 - June 2017

Leading all UX and visual design across web and apps. Contributing to product roadmap and strategy. Leading research, insight and testing. Design of new enquiries form, payments/bookings system and update to visual identity.

BBC UX&D - Radio & Music, GEL, News, Homepage - UX Designer

May 2013 - October 2016

Music site re-structure, find a track, iPlayer Radio recommendations & favourites, App Store videos. New responsive grid and new design patterns.

Education

2000 - 2010

Manchester School of Architecture - BA HONS Architecture

Poole Grammar School - A-Levels - Art, Media, History A, A, C, GCSEs - 11 grades A to C